<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Koowoy Devs</title>
    <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Koowoy Devs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 09:55:25 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://uk960214.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Django] Template Tag/Filter (Loop/Datetime)</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-08-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 09:55:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-08-06/</guid>
      <description>Make the First Element of a Django Template Loop Different from Others The method of adding and removing current class with JavaScript to give different styling and action needs an extra step with django. When elements are created with loops, adding current class to one of the elements will automatically copy them into all others, unless there is a way to set the first item of the loop.
{% for post in posts_list %} {% if forloop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Github] Team Project Tips, Solution when Gitignore is not Working</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-08-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 15:21:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-08-05/</guid>
      <description>Problem Since I was using Github in cooperation for the first time, there were a few problems I have encountered with pull and merges.
Before I pushed my working branch to Github, I should have checked whether an existing pull request exists, and if that were the case, the existing pull request should have be reviewed and merged first before I pushed my branch. This would have prevented me from facing merge conflicts after pushing to github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Test Build and Deploy with Heroku</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-08-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 16:50:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-08-03/</guid>
      <description>Reference Heroku Webhosting for Django - Python Django Dentist Website #12
Configuring Django Apps for Heroku
General   guincorn: Django uses &amp;ldquo;runserver&amp;rdquo; as the default package to run a server during development. However, when deploying with heroku, &amp;ldquo;gunicorn&amp;rdquo; should be used to run a server.
  whitenoise: In local environment, django is capable of searching for static files by itself. In deployment, static files are to be manually collected using &amp;ldquo;whitenoise&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidenote_21.07.31</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 23:33:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-07-31/</guid>
      <description>This is a really short note that might save loads of time When working with chrome, some things just might not work because the wrong codes that has been fixed might be saved in the cache and prevents the right code from working. Today this problem occurred when working with Redux. Make sure to get in the habit of using hard reload (ctrl + F5) when reloading in development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidenote_21.07.29</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-07-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 23:49:02 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-07-29/</guid>
      <description>Steps to try when pip doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly  Run in Administrative Mode Reinstall pip with py -m ensurepip --upgrade (pip documentation)  Alternative command when django-admin doesn&amp;rsquo;t work From Django Docs command not found: django-admin¶ django-admin should be on your system path if you installed Django via pip. If it’s not in your path, ensure you have your virtual environment activated and you can try running the equivalent command python -m django.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL of the Past: 20-10-10</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:48:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-10/</guid>
      <description>Promise  The Promise object represents the eventual completion (or failure) of an asynchronous operation and its resulting value.
 In simple words, promise is used to process async operation, and when successful it returns a single value. It is mainly used to process data received from a different source and display on the page.
Before promise, async operations were processed with a chain of callback functions, which, in complex cases, made the code very hard to read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Javascript] Conversion from if statement to OR expression | Deconstruction</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 17:49:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-19/</guid>
      <description>The following themes are newly learned features of Javascript.
Short-Circuit Evaluation and OR Expression While using the logical operators, for instance and, or, and not, there are cases where the assessment of the second value is irrelevant. For example in OR expressions, when the first value is true, the expression is true no matter the second value of the expression. In these cases, Javascript chooses not to evaluate the second value, and this is called &amp;ldquo;short-circuit evaluation&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting React App to Google Sheets using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 22:15:22 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-16/</guid>
      <description>Reference: For general structure - Youtube Channel Get __it Done!
For auto increment id on Google Sheets - Stack Overflow Question
Motivation For my react app, I wanted to create a page where I could ask for the user&amp;rsquo;s email and name, maybe for future marketing purposes. Although storing these kind of data would conventionally require a backend server and a database connected to it. However, I wanted this project to be as lightweight as possible, preferably a Front End only project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL of the Past: 20-10-07</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 14:14:23 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-07/</guid>
      <description>React - Create React App Creating a react app was&amp;hellip; harder than I expected, although Repl.it supported React template and even the Create React App template.
Concept of React With React, front end can be broken down into &amp;ldquo;Components&amp;rdquo;, which allows for further uses of the function later on.
Literally, it means that parts of html is written in pieces in javascript form, so that it can be written more efficiently with lots more extensibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy React App With Github Pages</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 22:27:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-09/</guid>
      <description>References:Youtube Tutorial by Telmo Sampaio Create-React-App Documentation
Although I thought the deployment part wouldn&amp;rsquo;t take that much time. But because of some minor mistakes I made in some stages, which was not explicitly explained by the create react app documentation, I had to start over a multiple times until I figured things out.
Basic Steps as explained by the documentation 1. Add homepage field to package.json The field could be placed in order in the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SVG in Create-React-App (color/text manipulation, download as png)</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:39:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-07-08/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was asked to build a small app that takes in user input and create a downloadable image using those inputs. The user inputs their name and three colors (using html color picker) and the result image renders according to those inputs.
SVG After researching for different ways to manipulate images, I came across &amp;lsquo;svg&amp;rsquo;. Svg stands for &amp;lsquo;scalable vector images&amp;rsquo;, and put short, instead of saving image pixel by pixel as in other image files, svg saves &amp;lsquo;paths&amp;rsquo; of the image and &amp;lsquo;draw&amp;rsquo; this paths when called.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Sidenote/JS] Using Stack for Maximum Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-06-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 22:57:42 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-06-28/</guid>
      <description>Solution Reference:
https://programmers.co.kr/questions/17409
Task https://programmers.co.kr/learn/courses/30/lessons/12973
Given a string of characters, if two of the same alphabet in a row is to be deleted until there is none left, check if this possible with the given string.
Solution function solution(s) { // Split string into array  let arr = s.split(&amp;#39;&amp;#39;); // Set temporary stack array  let temp = []; // If string length is odd number, return 0  if (arr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[JS/Problem Solving] Get Target Number</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 16:07:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-27/</guid>
      <description>Task https://programmers.co.kr/learn/courses/30/lessons/43165
Count how many combinations of adding and subtracting each element of the given array results the given target number.
Solution function solution(numbers, target) { let answer = 0; let nums = [...numbers]; const tar = target; // Recursive function  const getTarget = (arr, num, count) =&amp;gt; { // Get sum at every loop  let sum = arr.reduce((a, c) =&amp;gt; a + c, 0); // If sum matches target, increase answer  if(sum === num) { answer++; } // For every item in array, change to negative value, recursion  for (let i = count; i &amp;lt; arr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL of the Past: 20-10-03</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 22:17:41 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-03/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript - Advanced Loop Along with the for, while, do, and forEach loop, the topic in this section was the usage of for of and for in loop.
The idea is generally similar to the one of forEach loop, but the difference of &amp;lsquo;for in&amp;rsquo; loop compared to the other two was that &amp;lsquo;for in&amp;rsquo; was enumerating, while the other two were iterating. A more thorough explanation is provided by this link, to be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m still not 100% sure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidenote_21.06.24</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-06-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 23:22:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-06-24/</guid>
      <description>references:
File
sprintf
Task and Solution Code From a damaged (or deleted) card data, recover original jpeg images. [details]
My Solution #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;stdint.h&amp;gt; typedef uint8_t BYTE; int main(int argc, char *argv[]) { // Check if parameter validity  if (argc != 2) { printf(&amp;#34;Usage: ./recover image\n&amp;#34;); return 1; } // Open input file  char *infile = argv[1]; FILE *inptr = fopen(infile, &amp;#34;r&amp;#34;); if (inptr == NULL) { fprintf(stderr, &amp;#34;Could not open %s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index and Search (2021 Kakao Blind Recruitment)</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 23:12:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-24/</guid>
      <description>Task https://programmers.co.kr/learn/courses/30/lessons/72412;
My Solution referenced from:
 https://velog.io/@alvin/%ED%94%84%EB%A1%9C%EA%B7%B8%EB%9E%98%EB%A8%B8%EC%8A%A4-%EB%AC%B8%EC%A0%9C%ED%92%80%EC%9D%B4-%EC%88%9C%EC%9C%84-%EA%B2%80%EC%83%89-Javascript https://12bme.tistory.com/120  function solution(info, query) { let answer = []; // store every possible combination that every info can match to  let combinations = {}; const getCombinations = (arr, score, init) =&amp;gt; { let spec = arr.join(&amp;#39;&amp;#39;); let value = combinations[spec]; // add score to combination object  if (value) { combinations[spec].push(score); } else { combinations[spec] = [score]; } // recursive function, to loop through every possibility  for (let i = init; i &amp;lt; arr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL of the Past: 20-10-01</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 23:31:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/til_of_past/20-10-01/</guid>
      <description>For the Summer Vacation, I have decided to regularly upload the TILs I wrote last year on Notion onto the blog, for recap and archiving purposes.
20.10.01 JS - Advanced Arrays and Objects / ES 7, 8, 10 The lessons for today were so wide spread, starting with the advanced functions and new features of ES5 and ES6, but these were rather similar to the one&amp;rsquo;s that I have done last month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL - CS50x Week 5 Data Structure</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 13:24:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-22/</guid>
      <description>Until this lesson, the term &amp;ldquo;data structure&amp;rdquo; reminded me only of the &amp;ldquo;data types&amp;rdquo; that variables can have. But I learned that data structure rather referred to how multiple data is stored and accessed in different methods.
Array Though I&amp;rsquo;ve used arrays in so many different languages, since there were a lot of simplification applied to the arrays in Javascript and Python, I only came to know of the restrictions that arrays have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Github Profile</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:25:52 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-06-05/</guid>
      <description>After a long break from mending my Github, I returned and started with setting up my github profile.
Basics In order to set up the profile page add various personal details on the profile page, a new repository is needed, with the name set up as github username. (for instance, in my case, my id is uk960214, therefore I created a repository with the name &amp;ldquo;uk960214&amp;rdquo;)
The readme.md file on this repository will be shown in the profile page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[JS/Problem Solving] Getting the highest possible number</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-03-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 22:22:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-03-06/</guid>
      <description>Task Requirements A number between 0 and 1,000,000 and k that is smaller than the first number is given. When k amount of digit is removed, return the highest possible number.
My Attemps for Solution No.1) Using Combination On first thought, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of how big the number could be, and came up with the idea to find all possiblities and to compare these to find the maximum value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Sidenote/JS] Using Recursion to Get All Possible Combinations</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-03-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 21:33:37 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/sidenote/sidenote_21-03-06/</guid>
      <description>The definition of combination in mathematics is as follows:
 In mathematics, a combination is a selection of items from a collection, such that the order of selection does not matter. (from Wikipedia)
 In order to get all the possible selections, the following formula is used:
image-source
The first part refers to all the combination that includes a certain value, and the latter part refers to all the combinations that does not include that value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enlightenment of the Day 21.02.13</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-02-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 22:07:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-02-13/</guid>
      <description>Handling Edge Cases in Image Filtering / Understanding Rounding of Floats in C 1. Handling Edge Cases in Image Filtering Problem Using C, create a program that apllies different filters on images. Each pixel is stored in a two dimensional array.
Obsctacle When filtering the image with &amp;lsquo;blur&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;border&amp;rsquo; filter, for each pixel in the image, certain values of all surrounding pixels needs to be reached. However, the number of surrounding pixels vary depending on the location of the pixel, more precisely, depending on whether the pixel is in the corner, edge or the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Javascript Regex] Recommending Alternative ID</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-02-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 22:00:55 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-02-03/</guid>
      <description>Task Requirements The Rules for the ID  Length of the ID must be 3 to 15 characters.
  Only alphanumeric(lowercase) characters and [ -] , [ _ ], [ . ] are allowed.
  [ . ] can not be used at the beginning and the end, and cannot be used consecutively.
 Seven Steps in Creating Recommended ID Step 1. Change all the uppercase letters to lowercase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying the Loser from a Game of Word Chain</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-02-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 22:01:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-02-02/</guid>
      <description>Rule of the Game Certain number of players present a word in turns, that begins with the letter of the last word&amp;rsquo;s ending. For instance, if the last word was apple, the current player needs to present a word that starts with e. No word can be presented twice in the same game.
Therefore the loser is a. whose word presented didn&#39;t begin with the last word&#39;s ending(let&#39;s call this following the previous word) or b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enlightenment of the Day 21.02.01</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-02-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 21:03:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-02-01/</guid>
      <description>Sorting and Locking Pairs for Tideman (CS50 Problem Set 3) The Original Problem Explained (Tideman)  The Problem Encountered Although with the test sets provided with the example seemed to work just fine with the code I originally wrote, when graded, it showed that my code didn&amp;rsquo;t lock the pairs correctly (meaning it didn&amp;rsquo;t lock what it was supposed to, and locked pairs where it should have skipped).
1. Sorting Problem Instructions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enlightenment of the Day 21.01.21</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-01-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:58:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-01-21/</guid>
      <description>Getting Student with Highest Score Problem 3 Students are taking a multiple choice test with 5 answer options. Without actually solving the problem, they repeat the same pattern of numbers. When fed with the answer array, return the student who scored the highest.  Requirements 1. The pattern of each student is as follows: Student 1: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 1, 2 .... Student 2: 2, 1, 2, 3, 2, 4, 2, 5, 2, 1, 2, 3 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using C to Identify Valid Credit Card Numbers</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-01-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 01:14:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-01-20/</guid>
      <description>Problem Create a program that uses Luhn&amp;rsquo;s Algorithm to identify if the input number is a valid credit card number for AMEX, MASTERCARD, and VISA. Breaking Down the Problem Basic Characteristics of Credit Card Numbers 1. The numbers have specific **digits** (AMEX: 15, MASTER: 16, VISA: 13 or 16 ) 2. The **first two digits** of the number are also specific (AMEX: 34 or 37, MASTER: 51~55, VISA: 40~49)  Luhn&amp;rsquo;s Algorithm Not only does the number have to fit the requirements above, it also needs to be validated through Luhn&amp;rsquo;s Algorithm which is as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enlightenment of the Day 21.01.11</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-01-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:07:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/enlightenments/enlightenment-21-01-11/</guid>
      <description>Situation Solving the following task on Programmers (Link) Task  An interger array &amp;lsquo;numbers&amp;rsquo; is given. Create a function that returns an array consisting of sums of 2 numbers of different index sorted in an ascending order.
 Resitrictions   The length of &amp;lsquo;numbers&amp;rsquo; is between 2 to 100. All of the numbers of are bewtween 0 to 100.   Input/Output example     numbers result     [2, 1, 3, 4, 1] [2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7]   [5, 0, 2, 7] [2, 5, 7, 9, 12]     My Approach to the Solution   Initially    Logic Sort the input array in ascending order =&amp;gt; loop through the array using forEach =&amp;gt; in each iteration, map the array, adding the current value to the array =&amp;gt; add all that to a result array =&amp;gt; using Set, pick out unique values</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing a [github.io Blog] with Hugo and Github Pages</title>
      <link>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-01-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 23:15:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://uk960214.github.io/posts/til/21-01-09/</guid>
      <description>0. Prerequisites  Github is installed (Link to Github Desktop)  1. Install Hugo [for Windows 10]   Create a new folder with the name &amp;ldquo;Hugo&amp;rdquo; on C: directory.
  Inside C:\Hugo, create another new folder with the name &amp;ldquo;bin&amp;rdquo;.
  Download the latest version of Hugo for Windows (which is in .zip format) from Hugo Releases.
  Extract the zip file into the C:\Hugo\bin, which was created in Step 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
